<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Games on Azrea Amis</title><link>/tags/games/</link><description>Recent content in Games on Azrea Amis</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 13:14:25 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game Idea: "Annihilation: God's Will"</title><link>/posts/2019/05/09/game-idea-annihilation-gods-will/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 13:14:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/2019/05/09/game-idea-annihilation-gods-will/</guid><description>God created this world. Now, he&amp;rsquo;s finished with it.
I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure what medium best fits this story, but the idea started live as a story driven cRPG, so I&amp;rsquo;ll explain it like that first.
Story The story begins in the holy city of Kalstar, rumored to the oldest city in the world, and home to the God&amp;rsquo;s Grand Temple. In the final chapter of God&amp;rsquo;s bible, He states that the world will end precisely 1000 years after it started.</description></item><item><title>Intentional Limit Breaks in Video Games</title><link>/posts/2019/01/14/intentional-limit-breaks-in-video-games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 11:58:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>/posts/2019/01/14/intentional-limit-breaks-in-video-games/</guid><description>When building consumer software, it&amp;rsquo;s a widely held belief that the software shouldn&amp;rsquo;t crash, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t hang (or ignore user input), and should generally remain &amp;ldquo;in control.&amp;rdquo; Users don&amp;rsquo;t like software that crashes and loses their progress, and they don&amp;rsquo;t react well to software that freezes: they tend to spam buttons, making the problem worse.
This is just as important and much harder for video games. Video games are among the most complex and demanding software being produced commercially, and they&amp;rsquo;re likely the most complex and demanding software the average consumer will ever run.</description></item><item><title>Game Idea: Compressed Dungeons, pt. 1</title><link>/posts/2018/05/04/game-idea-compressed-dungeons-pt.-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 09:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018/05/04/game-idea-compressed-dungeons-pt.-1/</guid><description>tldr: moba keystone dungeons
Traditional cRPGs are, in general, united by a strong emphasis on character progression. By playing the game, and completing challenges, your character gains experience, sometimes represented by literal experience points, and becomes stronger, more capable, and better equipped for even more challenging encounters. This is frequently associated with numerical increases (allowing you to crush old content with pure numerical advantage), and in many cases, although you grow stronger your enemies do to at a carefully controlled rate that matches yours, and in some cases comparatively exceeds yours, making later enemies harder and harder to kill so the gameplay still has a positive difficulty curve.</description></item></channel></rss>